So here we have our container which is set to grid.
这里我们有一个设置为 grid 的 container 容器
Let's make it as wide as possible.
我们设置宽度为 100%
As you're used to, we have grid template rows and grid template columns,
和之前一样 我们设置 grid-template-rows 和 grid-template-columnds 属性
followed by a grid gap.
以及 grid-gap
The new part here is grid template areas.
然后就是 grid-template-areas 这个新属性了
For this grid template area,
这里
I've simply used top top,
我们设置了 top top
bottom left, bottom right.
bottom left  和 bottom right 几个区域
Now, here we can see I've given each of the elements an id.
这里 我给每个元素都设置了一个 id 属性
This id can be used to put each of these elements into the place on the grid we want.
通过这些 id 我们可以将元素放置在网格中的对应区域
So for example, if I want let's say box 1 to be on top all the way,
比如 如果我们想放置 box 1 在 top 区域内
I can just say grid area top which is
我可以设置 grid-area 属性为 top
defined here as taking up two columns on the top row,
在这里它会占据顶部一行中的两列
and then I'm going to put two on the bottom left
然后我们将 box 2 放置在 bottomLeft 区域
and three on the bottom right boom.
将 box 3 放置在 bottomRight 区域
There you can see. In our top,
现在你可以看到 在 top 区域
we have box 1,
我们放置了 box 1 元素
which is going across both the columns in the first row.
它占据了第一行中的两列空间
Here we have grid template area's top top,
也就是 grid-template-areas 中的 top top 区域
and then box two which has been put on the bottom left if here on the bottom left,
box 2 被放置在了 bottomLeft 区域 也就是左下角的位置
and three is here on the bottom right.
然后 box 3 被放置在 bottomRight 区域
It's very easy to switch these around.
想要交换它们的位置也非常方便
So we could just say actually we want one on the bottom left,
我们可以把 box 1 放在 bottomLeft 区域
and we want two on the top.
把 box 2 放置在 top 区域
Now we have box 2 on the top,
好了 现在 box 2 显示在了上方
box 1 on the bottom left,
而 box 1 则显示在了左下角
and box 3 on the bottom right.
box 3 还是在右下角区域
This is an example of using named grid areas in order to create your master layout.
这就是使用 CSS grid 创建网页布局的一个例子
But this is just a basic example.
但是这只是一个基础的例子
Let's take a look at one that maybe has a little more practical.
让我们来看一个更实用的例子
Here you can see I've set up what could be the wire frame for a very basic blog.
这里你可以看到一个基础的博客网站页面 用线框区分出了不同区域
We have a header, a sidebar,
有一个 header 区域 sidebar 区域
content, and a footer.
content 以及 footer 区域
Here, I've set up my grid template columns,
这里 我已经设置好了 grid-template-columns
my grid template rows.
和 grid-template-rows 属性
Now in grid template areas,
然后在 grid-template-areas 这里
I've set up a grid that actually uses 1,
我设置了一个 hd 区域
2, 3, 4, 5, 6,
它占据了 1 2 3 4 5 6
7, 8 columns across.
7 8 个列的空间
As you'll notice, it's eight columns across on each line 1,
这里你应该注意到了 我们在一行也设置了 8 列
2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7, 8.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
It's very important that when making named grid template areas,
因为你的 grid-template-areas 中的命名空间
you have to stay consistent.
设置必须具有一致性
So you can't have three columns on
所以如果你第一行设置了 3 列
the first row without matching it to the second and the third.
那么你第二行也必须和它匹配才行
Here we can see we've given each of them a grid
这里我们设置了 grid-area 属性
area corresponding to the grid that we've set up.
它们和我们在上面设置的区域相对应
So we have our header going all the way across,
所以我们的 header 元素会占据整行的空间
sidebar here, and then our main is in content.
sidebar 在这里 然后是我们的 main 元素
So one issue you may have noticed is that
但是你可以看到这里
our sidebar was actually taking up more room than our content here,
sidebar 实际上占据了过多的空间
which is an issue with the way that we have set up the columns.
这是由于我们设置的 column 所占据的空间大小导致的
So what I've done in the code is I've come back to the columns,
所以我们回到上面设置列空间的地方
and I've set it so that our first column is just 30
我们设置第一列为 30 像素
pixels wide which are sidebar stretching across,
sidebar 会占据它的空间
and then our second column is 300 pixels wide.
然后第二列设置为 300 像素宽
So we can see here that the only one that this divides up is our sidebar and content.
在这里我们可以看见只有 sidebar 和 content 被区分成了 2 部分区域
Because here we have our header stretching across the whole entire top,
因为我们的 header 占据了顶部的整行空间
and our footer stretching across the whole entire bottom.
footer 也占据了最下面的整行空间
Another thing that I think we can do we'll find out together is we could change our grid
另外我们也可以改变我们的网格布局
here so that our main-content took up more of the grid that we set up.
来让我们的 main 内容区域占据更多的空间
That works very well.
好了
Now we can see that the sidebar is taking up even less room,
现在 sidebar 占据了更少的空间
and maybe what we want to do is only give it one column in our location setup.
或许我们只想让它占据一列的空间
Maybe we want to keep it at two.
或者干脆就让它占据两列空间
So this is how you can use CSS grid with
显而易见 你可以使用 CSS grid 中的 grid-template-areas
grid template areas to create your own custom layouts.
来灵活创建你想要的页面布局
Coming up in the next lessons,
在下一节课程中
we're going to look at how to fill out some of the content in
我们会看看如何填充一些内容区域
here to create first your own blog page,
来创建你的第一个博客网站
and then second a series of linked pages to individual posts.
并和一些单独的帖子页面关联起来
This is made so much easier by creating a head
通过 CSS grid 你可以很轻松的
of time layouts with CSS grid for each page.
搭建出每个页面的布局
Let's learn more about what that could look like.
让我们一起来看一看吧